ALEKSEI VASKO

Lead QA Engineer

CONTACT

E-mail

alexei.vasko@outlook.com

Phone

+49 176 34385473

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/alexeivasko

Location

Berlin, Germany

SKILLS Testing Tools

Cucumber, Selenium, Appium, Watir, TestRail, Zephyr, BrowserStack, Charles proxy, Postman, mitmproxy

Tools

Jira, Confluence, Favro, Trello, git, Sourcetree, Jenkins, Swagger, Phrase, Contentful, Sentry, Firebase, Google Play Store

Programming Languages

Ruby, Java, HTML5, CSS, XML

Languages

English — fluent
German — elementary
Estonian — intermediate
Russian — native

PROFILE

I am a software QA engineer with 7+ years of experience in web & mobile apps testing. I learnt the basics of testing from the best QA engineers in industry at HERE Berlin. Since that I have developed my own motto: "Explore. Think. Test. Review." It helps me to structure the work, communicate with colleagues, achieve company goals and reduce amount of bugs & defects.

EXPERIENCE

Lead QA engineer, nebenan.de (2017 — Present)

- Guarantee 99% availability of 7 platforms. Up to date crash-free statistics for android: 99.97% & iOS: 99.87% (stack: ruby on rails (BE), react (FE), java/kotlin & swift)
- Built the end-to-end test system for front-and back-end to ensure stability of the platforms (stack: ruby & cucumber)
- Hired, onboarded, guided & lead the QA team of 5 members
- Increased the productivity by 50% after introducing Kanban methodology & Jira software

QA engineer, <u>nebenan.de</u> (2016 — 2017)

- Set up the mobile testing system to keep crash-free statistics >99%
- Convinced to change user flows & navigation that showed 5% increase monthly return users

Navigation software tester, HERE Berlin (2014 — 2016)

- Conducted "Voice guidance assistant" in-house survey used in the car navigation of millions cars world wide
- Performed alfa-testing of HereWeGo apps with 10+ millions users (platforms: android & iOS)
- Adopted guidance assistant automation tests for international markets (tech stack: ruby & cucumber)
- Gained knowledge of Agile principles by using Scrum methodology

EDUCATION

Technische Universität Berlin / Master of Science

Berlin, Germany (2012 — 2016)

• Processed the development life cycle of an android app from the thesis topic "Development of an indoor location-based services information system" to publishing in Google Play store

Tallinn University of Applied Sciences / Bachelor of Science

Tallinn, Estonia (2006 — 2010)